Falling leaves again...
It's going to be tough sweeping
tomorrow morning.
Looks like that's going to be tough, too.
Ms. Sayaka.
Isn't there any way that I can be of help?
Oh, Kobato!
Welcome home!
Hello everybody.
Were you all out somewhere this afternoon?
Yes. There was a meeting at their
school for the coming bazaar.
Bazaar?
Everybody brings something.
And we sell it and use
the money for the school.
That's it!
Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
...Mysterious Life Form.
A bazaar!
Ms. Sayaka, let's have a bazaar!
What?
We can sell all kinds of things, lots of it,
and make money to pay off the debt!
Kobato?
Account Book
If we pay off the debt, the kindergarten
doesn't have to move out, right?
Account Book
Right? Let's do it! A bazaar!
But Kobato...
If the debt was small enough for a bazaar to
cover, we'd have paid it off ages ago!
Fujimoto?
It's one thing for a big school to have one,
but we're just a tiny kindergarten.
It's not going to be much of a bazaar.
It's just not worth it.
I'm sorry! I got carried away!
I'll go and sweep out front now!
Frankly speaking, if we do a bazaar and it
doesn't work out, it would be hardest on Kobato.
So I understand why you discouraged her.
But that was wrong, the way you said that.
Being overly blunt can make you a mean person.
I...
I got all excited and carried away.
Fujimoto and Ms. Sayaka must
think I'm pretty silly.
I am pretty silly, aren't I?
Yeah, you are pretty silly.
But I see nothing wrong with your enthusiasm.
Ioryogi-san!
Hey! Don't hug me! That's annoying!
Kobato?
Ms. Sayaka?
Let's do it. A bazaar.
Huh?
Bazaar?
We'll all bring things from home
that we no longer need,
or things we made and sell them
here at the kindergarten.
We can play store!
I want to have a fried noodle shop!
That sounds good, too.
I've written the details in your agendas
so be sure to show someone at home.
Okay!
Let's go for it!
Yeah!
Fujimoto.
Kobato seems to be feeling much
better now. Isn't that wonderful?
It's none of my business.
Bye-bye!
Ms. Sayaka, see you tomorrow!
Yes, goodbye!
Bazaar...
(Yomogi) Kindergarten
Bazaar
Bazaar...
(Yomogi) Kindergarten
Bazaar
What's this?
It's a puppy!
And that one?
A kitty!
Don't you think you're being
unkind to cats and dogs?
What can she say? He's telling the truth.
Have some tea.
Thank you very much.
Did you draw this, Kobato?
Yes!
It's very good.
Really. That's a really cute duck and sheep!
Well then, I've got to go now.
Are you working?
Yes.
Don't push yourself.
I'm not. Ms. Sayaka, you too.
Please take it easy.
So that's how Fujimoto smiles.
Mysterious Life Form
Goodbye.
He behaves like a little boy sometimes.
I think he likes you, Kobato.
What?!
Really.
He's not very good at showing his
honest feelings. Just like that man.
That man?
Kobato! Thank you for all of your help today.
Let's continue bazaar preparations tomorrow.
When she said, "that man..."
Could she have been talking
about her husband?
You once ordered a birthday cake
for your husband, didn't you?
Uh... yes...
Could be.
She said he's not good at showing his honest
feelings. I wonder what he's like.
Beats me.
It's a mystery.
Not as much of a mystery as
your drawings, Dobato!
You're mean!
Wow!
Thank you, everyone!
What's this?
Teru teru bozu dolls!
Teru teru bozu?
Um, they're weather dolls. You hang
them up to make it sunny outside.
I wonder who brought them.
Naomi, did you make these?
Mhm.
The weather's usually good when
I make the teru teru bozu dolls.
The day of the picnic... and when we
went to the pool, it became sunny.
Pretty amazing weather dolls, aren't they?
I wonder if they'll sell.
Sure! I'll make something too.
Let's line them up for sale together.
Let's!
So. Let's start putting price tags on
the things you all brought.
Okay, write them nice and big here.
Kobato...
Yes Naomi?
If a lot of people buy weather dolls,
can the kindergarten stay?
Yes, It sure can.
Um, well... my mommy's going to...
My mommy's going to have a baby soon.
That's wonderful! Congratulations!
So you see...
Mommy is taking time off
work starting this month,
but when the baby gets bigger,
she's going to work again.
She wants to have the baby come
to Yomogi Kindergarten.
And because I'm going to be the big sister,
I'll come to pick her up!
Then I'll still be able to see you
and Ms. Sayaka every day!
I want to see you when you're a big sister, too!
Everybody, let's make this happen!
Yes!
Yomogi Kindergarten
Bazaar
Yes!
Yomogi Kindergarten
Bazaar
Oh, we worked very late.
Are you with Yomogi Kindergarten?
Huh?
Ah, yes!
I recognize your voice.
I talked to you on the phone.
And you are?
I'm a debt collector.
I'm shutting down the kindergarten.
I'm not extending the repayment deadline.
That phone call...
Working overtime?
No! We were putting up posters
for the bazaar and we...!
You are a bad man so I tell you nothing!
You're quite a character. I also thought
so when we talked over the phone.
Did you give my message to Sayaka?
That's she's not getting an extension?
Tell her also that you saw me here today.
And that when the due date arrives,
I'm going to shut down the kindergarten.
You can't do that!
I don't care if children are attending.
Tell her if she doesn't want anyone injured,
to pack her things and go.
See you around, Kobato.
Do you think he's serious...
about shutting down the kindergarten?
Even if children are attending... that's terrible.
How can he look so kind and
say such awful things?
That man scares me.
What kind of a man?
F-Fujimoto! Were you listening?
I overheard you talking to yourself
in that big voice of yours!
I wasn't talking to myself...
What was he like?
H-He didn't give me his name.
He just smiled a lot.
Oh, and he was calling
Ms. Sayaka just "Sayaka."
Okiura...
Huh?
Someone you know?
Did Ms. Sayaka meet him?
N-No... After he talked to me, he just left.
Don't say a word to her.
Don't tell Ms. Sayaka that you saw him.
But!
Just keep your mouth shut about it.
Why did you go there? You make more trouble
for Ms. Sayaka and I won't stand for it.
Now you listen to me. Don't be showing
your face at her place either.
That man...
Huh?
His name is Okiura, isn't it? I wonder
what his connection to Ms. Sayaka is.
Why that's totally obvious!
Huh?
That woman Sayaka was apparently married
and her last name is the same as that man's.
And he calls her Sayaka!
WHAT?! Then that man is
Ms. Sayaka's husband?!
Why would he want to put
the kindergarten under?
Don't you get yourself too involved in this case.
Huh?
Besides, don't you have things to do?
You won't be able to go where you want to go
until that bottle is full, you know that?
But... I'm worried...
And? What is that you're sewing?
It's a mascot!
I'm making it from cloth Ms. Chitose gave me!
Is it a penguin?
It's a rabbit.
Those are ears?!
Call it what you like! Okay, it's a penguin then!
Anyway, I am going to do my best to
see that the bazaar is a success!
Then, you plan to mass-produce
that mysterious life form?!
Hey, you're beginning to sound like Fujimoto!
You are mean!
Yomogi Kindergarten
Bazaar Hall
Looks like heavy clouds today.
It'll be all right!
The clouds will clear, I'm sure.
I certainly hope so.
Ioryogi-san?
I'll bring you something that will surely sell.
Thank you very much!
Let's all give it our best today!
Yes!
I'm sure the weather dolls will
turn it into nice weather.
Yeah!
Kobato.
Don't fall down, okay?
We're going to be selling drinks and stuff too.
I-I will not fall down.
You'll fall down.
Huh!
I will not! I refuse to fall down!
You two really get along well.
We do not get along.
We don't!
Oh this. Fujimoto had this donated from work.
Thank you very much.
What did I tell you? You fell.
I'm sorry.
Don't get your hopes up too high.
Huh?
Oh no, I've got to go!
Kobato, You fell down after all.
We aren't getting any customers.
We put all those posters up together.
Don't worry.
Your mothers probably won't be
here until much later,
but other customers will be
showing up soon, I'm sure.
Really?
What if nobody comes?
It's all because I suggested having a bazaar.
Hello.
Chitose!
Kobato told us and we've been
looking forward to it.
Weren't we?
Right?
Right!
Would you like some fried noodles?
We've got iced coffee, too.
Or café au lait if you like.
Thank you for coming.
We were really looking forward to it.
Chiho and Chise, too. But...
When we looked today, the posters were gone
so we were worried that it had been canceled.
What?
Oh, no...
Don't tell me that guy's responsible for this.
Kobato?!
I'm going to tell everybody that the
bazaar has not been canceled!
Isn't it kind of late for that?!
It's not too late! People still may come!
But still, this is just a tiny little bazaar.
Even so, it would be worth it if I can get even
one more person to come! Because...
Because we all, all the children
worked very hard on this!
All of us... together...
Kobato...
Fujimoto, you too! Didn't you?!
Kobato's a good kid.
She really is.
Fujimoto?
Well she says she's going to get people to come,
I'd better get some coffee ready.
A bit twisted, but he's a good kid too.
Yes.
A chicken?
A seal?
Still nobody.
Although it's stopped raining.
Even the sun's coming out.
Good afternoon.
Is this where the Bazaar is?
Yes.
Kobato came to tell me about it and
I thought I'd come for a look.
Hey, this is it here!
I heard you're having a bazaar.
Oh, perhaps I can find a bargain.
This looks like fun.
Where do you want to go first?
Welcome!
Looks busy.
Domoto...
Yeah, Kobato told me.
Hasn't she come back yet?
Can I get an iced coffee?
Ah, yes! Teacher Fujimoto,
one iced coffee please!
Here you are.
Hey. There was this young lady,
she's walking the streets shouting,
"Bazaar at Yomogi Kindergarten," you know...
Bazaar everybody!
Like she was putting everything she had into it.
So well I said, "Hey, I'll check it out later,"
and she grabbed my hand and
started shaking it like mad.
Thank you very much!
I can just see it.
Sounds just like her.
Mommy!
Naomi, I'm sorry I'm late.
Look at all the customers you have.
Yeah.
Good thing the weather cleared up.
Mhm!
Bazaar today at Yomogi Kindergarten!
Everybody, please come and check it out!
Yomogi Kindergarten Bazaar!
It's happening right now!
Hito wa mina tonde mitai no ni
Juuryoku ni damasareterunda
Dare mo honto wa toberunda yo
Ano ko ga anna ni kanashisou na no wa
Jibun no kage wo
Dokoka ni wasurete kichatta kara kamo
Sore nara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ni ietara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ga waraeba
Ittari kitari ureshiku naru
Kimi ga shiawase ni naru
Shinpai nante iranai yo
Issho ni iru kara
Ureshikuttemo namida ga deru nante
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Mysterious Life Form II.
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Mysterious Life Form II.